Jose R. Velazquez Gonzalez

806-1090 Johnson St., Victoria, BC, Canada V8V 0B3 | 🖂 joserobertovg@gmail.com | ① (778) 700-6364 | 💂 https://analystjose.com/

Summary

Fast-learning business professional with 12+ years' experience in diverse industries, developing strong analytical and problem-solving skills from operations to management in diverse industries like e-commerce, finance, insurance, telecommunications, and real estate. Enthusiastic about analyzing and interpreting data to provide actionable insights to drive growth using tools such as Excel, SQL, and Tableau, among other technical skills as shown on my portfolio website.

Skills

Programming Languages: SQL (stored procedures, functions), R (dplyr, ggplot, shiny), Python (Pandas, NumPy, matplotlib) **Software:** Excel (VBA, Power Query), Tableau, Tableau Prep, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, RStudio, Jupyter Notebooks, Office 365

Work Experience

Derivatives Trader | Remote

Dec 2011 - Present

- Traded diverse CFD's markets including Forex, Indices, Commodities, Futures, and Crypto, using a rule-based trading system.
- Used technical analysis involving price action, market structure, moving averages, support and resistance, and supply and demand.

Online Sales at Vetta | Remote

Mar 2020 - May 2022

- Cleaned, transformed, and analysed sales data to create reports and dashboards using Excel and Tableau.
- Built e-commerce stores (Shopify and Mercado Libre) including layout, themes, descriptions, images, and prices for 200+ products.
- Delivered prompt B2B customer service on Messenger, WhatsApp, and e-mail, reducing response times to less than 1 hour.

Operations Auditor at Coppel | Zacatecas, Mexico

Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

- Analyzed individual store operations from databases to select unusual and/or suspicious operations for fraud prevention.
- Performed retail stores, warehouses, and distribution centers audits, evaluating performance, and generating auditing reports.
- Reviewed processes, documents, and inventories to generate risk assessment reports for managers to make informed decisions.

Insurance Agent at Seguros Monterrey New York Life | SLP, Mexico

Jul 2015 - Jan 2017

- Arranged meetings evaluate individual clients' needs and goals to create long-term savings, investing, and retirement plans.
- Explained in detail each individual policy coverage as per the current law of insurances and sureties.
- Certified insurance agent in Mexico by CNSF (National Insurance and Surety Commission).

Customer Service at Telcel | SLP, Mexico

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015

- Delivered outstanding face-to-face customer service, sales, quotation, billing, problem solving and client retention.
- Managed confidential information of hundreds of customers, creating and updating information on ERP.

Administrative Assistant at Atena Bienes Raices | SLP, Mexico

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

- Processed documents, collected client information, and filled out loan approval forms with banks and government agencies.
- Created and updated an Excel database with hundreds of homes listings, for salespersons to easily access the properties features.

Education

Business Administration Certificate

University of Victoria | Victoria, BC, Canada | Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

Business Intelligence and Data Analytics (BIDA) Certificate

University of Victoria | Victoria, BC, Canada | Sep 2021 – Mar 2022

Bachelor of Business Administration

Minor in Finance | Universidad del Valle de Mexico | SLP, Mexico | Aug 2005 – Dec 2009